

# **Xavier Garcia**

Creative Front-end Developer

Phone: +31 636 458 616 Web: http://whoisxavier.com/ E-mail: garcia.xavier@gmail.com

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2020-Current	<b>Technical Director.</b> MediaMonks. Amsterdam, Netherlands. Leading a global team for development, conceptualization and design of Dynamic Remarketing campaigns, Responsive layouts and Complex Display Advertising for international brands across the world (AMER, EMEA, APAC) with a focus in the automotive industry.
2018-2020	<b>Rich Media Specialist.</b> Das Banner B.V. Amsterdam, Netherlands. Development, conceptualization and design of digital marketing campaigns and Rich Media Advertising for brands such as BMW, Huawei, Adidas, Mini, Rabo Bank, FBTO, Nescafe.
2017-2018	<b>Senior Front-End Designer.</b> AGCS B.V. Amsterdam, Netherlands. Digital Production Agency specialized in the development and design of digital marketing campaigns for brands such as Yamaha Motors, Universal Pictures, Ubisoft, Deustche Bank, Volvo.
2010-2016	<b>Lead Art Director. LG Electronics Spain.</b> Madrid, Spain. In-house Agency for LG Electronics Spain, in charge of Brand Language, BTL Department, and In-Store Communication in association with the LG Marketing Department.
2008-2010	Art Director. PICA Studio. Buenos Aires, Argentina.  Art Direction for THC Magazine, Aperiódico Psicoanalítico, Club del Disco, Tutú Marambá.
2007	<b>Art Direction Internship.</b> Leo Burnett Argentina. Buenos Aires, Argentina. Working in the Creative Department for brands such as Fiat, Arcor, Bwin.
2005-2006	Creative Trainee. QUINCE Publicidad. Madrid, Spain. Working in the Creative Department for brands such as FLEX, Aenor, Alhambra, Aurgi.

# **EDUCATION**

2013-2014	Professional Course in Web Applications Development. CICE Professional School. Madrid, Spain.
2012-2013	Course in Mobile Applications Development (iOS & Android) CICE Professional School. Madrid, Spain.
2009	Master's Degree in Art Direction. Underground Escuela de Creativos. Buenos Aires, Argentina.
2007-2008	Master's Degree in Creative Advertising. Escuela Superior de Creativos Publicitarios. Buenos Aires, Argentina.
2006	Master's Degree in Brand Positioning and Architecture. ESIC Business School/Florida University. Madrid, Spain.
2003-2006	Bachelor's Degree in Advertising and Public Relations ESIC Business School. Madrid, Spain.



## Xavier Garcia

Creative Front-end Developer

Phone: +31 636 458 616 Web: http://whoisxavier.com/ E-mail: garcia.xavier@gmail.com

#### **KNOWLEDGE & SKILLS**

- Knowledge in Software Development, UX & Web Design :
- Web Development & Design: HTML5, CSS, SVG, Javascript. Front-end animations (Greensock, CSS, Canvas), SVG in JS, ThreeJS, React, Vue.js, Webpack, Laravel, git
- Adobe Creative Cloud License (Master Collection): Illustrator CC, Photoshop CC, InDesign CC, After Effects CC, Premiere CC, Lightroom CC.
- Sketch & Figma
- Proficiency with Cinema 4D, Corel Painter 11 and Aperture
- Apple iOS Developer License: Knowledge in Obective-C programming, App development and UX design with Xcode.
- Android Developer License: Knowledge in Java programming, App development and UX design for Android
- Languages: Fluent in English (spoken and written), Spanish (native), Nederlands B1 level.

#### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a Creative Developer currently living in Amsterdam. I posses a wide range of abilities that combine the use of the latest design and development tools with problem solving through creative thinking and conceptualization.

Furthermore, my expert knowledge of the Adobe Creative Cloud Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, After Effects, Premiere, Animate...) plus my knowledge with development tools for web and mobile applications (HTML, CSS, SVG, Javascript, React, Vue.js, GSAP) will allow me to help to develop and implement the brand's communication strategies.

I have experience managing a team of people to maintain a cohesive look across all the communication strategies. I work closely with clients and stakeholders to translate and convey technical specifications in layman terms while I make sure that the team's technical performance meets client and stakeholder needs. I have a proven track record of successfully leading teams and delivering digital projects I welcome the opportunity to discuss how my skills and experience make me a strong fit for this role.